-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
非常感谢 先生 多施舍一点...
Thank you very much, sir.Even great..
愿主保佑你 先生
God bless you, sir.
你是个好人
You're a gentlemen,
十全十美的大好人
a very perfect gentle Knight.
祝你们日安 先生们
Good day you all sir.
谢谢你 先生
Oh thank you sir.
多施舍点吧
Oh filling my cup running over.
愿你的善良人人皆知
May your sweetness never blush unseen
我感激不尽 先生
My gratitude knows no bounds sir.
我是你们的奴仆 衰弱且卑贱
Here I sit your slave weak and despised.
威廉・莎士比亚
William Shakespeare.
哦 是啊 我在那儿 他也是...
Oh yeah, i was there.And so was he..
有福的人是精神上的贫乏者 先生
Blessed are the poor in spirit, sir.
有福的人是精神上的贫乏者
Blessed are the poor in spirit
因为你们的是天国 先生(出自汤姆历险记一书)
for yours is the kingdom of heaven sir.
帮帮忙吧!救命!不要!
Help!Help!Help!Please!
但我们半个月前就安排好了
But we arranged it two weeks ago.
在我的俱乐部用晚餐
We were to have supper at my club.
是的
Yes.
他今天早上还跟我提过
He did mention it to me this morning.
就在一位女士来电前
It was just before the lady called.
女士?
Lady?
哪位女士?
Which lady?
我不知道她的名字
Well I don't know her name
但那位女士来电后福尔摩斯先生就出去了
but the lady called and Mr. Holmes went out.
既然那样 我得好好利用这个晚上
In that case I shall have take advantage of an early night.
我得去开门了
I must answer the door.
当然
Of course.
可能会有点线索
Might be a clue.
希望我没有打扰你们
I hope I'm not being a nuisance.
他肯定不会在意的
Oh he won't mind I'm sure,
他心肠最好了
he's the kindest of men.
惠特尼太太想见你 医生
Mrs. Whitney to see you Doctor.
凯特 真让人意外
Kate, this is a surprise.
不让人愉快的意外 约翰
Not a pleasant one I fear John.
谢谢 赫德森太太
Thank you Mrs. Hudson.
来点茶吧
Perhaps some tea.
太感谢了
That would be most welcome.
请原谅我带来这么多麻烦
You must forgive me for causing so much trouble...
一点也不麻烦 请坐
You're causing us no trouble at all, please.
你的助手告诉我
Your assistant told me
你在和福尔摩斯先生共进晚餐
that you were dining with Mr. Holmes.
你到诊所去了
Oh I see you've been to the surgery.
就在你刚离开的时候
And you had just left.
正如你所见 福尔摩斯先生
Well Mr. Holmes has disappeared without trace
不知道去哪了
as you can see.
既然如此
In that case,
我就更不该麻烦你了
I really shouldn't bother you with my problems.
每隔一段时间 福尔摩斯先生
Oh Mr. Holmes disappears without trace
就会销声匿迹一次
at regular intervals.
大可不必担心
There's really no cause for alarm,
好奇倒会有点
only curiosity.
但你为什么想见我呢?
But why did you want to see me?
如果你病了
If you're ill
不该穿过整个伦敦来这里
you should not be traveling across London.
我没生病
I am not ill.
是艾萨
It's Isa.
如果艾萨病了 我可以去你家拜访他
Well if Isa is ill I can visit him at home.
他不在家
He's not at home.
他也人间蒸发了?
He too has disappeared without trace?
你应该能猜到他在干什么
You can probably guess what he's doing.
我想他又沉迷于他的烟瘾中了
I imagine he's indulging his addiction.
鸦片?
Opium?
恐怕是的
I fear so.
这也不是第一次了吧?
Well he's done this before has he not?
是什么原因让这次
What makes this circumstance
如此特别?
so very different?
通常他这种放纵
Well normally his orgies
都不会超过一天
are confined to one day.
他早上出门
He leaves the house in the morning
晚上就会回家
and returns in the evening,
苍白且非常虚弱
pale and shattered.
而这次呢?
And this time?
我已经有两天
I have not seen Isa
没见过艾萨了
for forty-eight hours.
你是否知道他
Well have you the remotest idea
可能去哪里了吗?
where he might be?
有一个房子
There is an establishment
叫黄金酒馆
called the Bar of Gold
就在上天鹅闸巷
in Upper Swandam Lane,
我确信他在那里
I believe he is there
但我不敢一个人去
but I dare not go there alone.
不 不 任何一个体面的女士
Oh no, no,no respectable woman
都不会只身走进那肮脏的小巷
would go within a hundred miles of that
百里的范围内
vile alley unaccompanied.
你愿意跟我一起去吗?
Will you come with me?
不      但...
No.        But...
我将独自前往
No I shall go there on my own.
你先回家
You will go home
如果你的丈夫真的在你所想的那个地方
and if you're husband is where you think he is
我保证在两小时内
I guarantee to have him back with you
他会回到你身边
within two hours.
尽管我不敢想象
Though I dare not imagine
他届时的状况
what state he'll be in.
你的茶 医生
Your tea Doctor.
很抱歉 赫德森太太
My apologies Mrs. Hudson,
我不用茶了 我要出去了
I shall not require tea,I'm going out
但惠特尼太太得来点茶
but Mrs. Whitney will take tea.
那福尔摩斯先生回来时
And what am I to tell Mr. Holmes
我该如何告诉他呢?
should he return?
就说我消失得无影无踪了
Tell him I've disappeared without trace.
麻烦你 车夫 到上天鹅闸巷
Upper Swandam Lane please cabbie.
我时常会思忖
I sometimes wonder
究竟男人是否会成熟
whether men ever truly grow up.
他们似乎永远都长不大
They seem to remain little boys forever.
赫德森太太 你有这样想过吗?
Do you wonder about that Mrs. Hudson?
没有 惠特尼太太
No, Mrs. Whitney.
我从不这样想
I don't wonder about it.
我早就知道
I know it
他们总是需要我们在事后抚慰他们
and they always need us to kiss them better afterwards,
当然 用言语抚慰
in a matter of speaking of course.
不用了 谢谢
No thank you.
我不会久留
I've not come here to stay.
我是来找一位朋友的
There's a friend of mine here.
我想找艾萨・惠特尼先生
I just wish to speak to Mr. Isa Whitney.
艾萨?
Isa?
天啊
My God.
华生
Watson.
几点了?
What's the time?
十一点
It's eleven.
今天星期几?
What's the day?
十九号 星期五
Friday the nineteenth.
我还以为是星期三呢
I thought it was Wednesday.
就是星期三
It is Wednesday.
你想吓唬我
You're trying to frighten me.
你的妻子已经在家
Your wife has been waiting for you
等你两天了
to return home for two days.
两天?
Two days?
不可能
Surely not.
几个小时吧
A few hours perhaps.
三管
Three pipes,
四管
four pipes,
我不记得了
I forget.
外面有辆马车
I've got a cab outside
你现在就得回家!
you're going home now!
一定得回吗?
Must I?
如果你还在乎我们的友谊 你妻子的爱
If you value my friendship. Your wife's love
可怜的凯特
Oh poor Kate.
走吧
Come on.
我还得付钱
I have to pay.
我还欠店主钱
I owe the manager money.
你不必为
You don't have to pay
你的自我毁灭而付钱
for your own destruction.
我来处理
I'll see to it.
快离开这个糟糕的地方
Just get out of this dreadful place.
放手!
Let go!
把你的手拿开!
Get your hands off!
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
你跑到这种鬼地方来干什么!
What on earth are you doing in this den?
我在处理自己的事情
I'm going about my business.
你的马车在外面?
You have a cab outside?
是的
Yes.
快把他送回家吧
I pray send him home.
他已经受不了任何折腾了
He looks too limp to get into any kind of mischief.
五分钟后见      好
I'll see you in five minutes.      All right.
把这个给房子里的女士
Give this to the lady of the house.
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
是我 先生
I sir.
在那里见到你让我非常吃惊
I was certainly surprised to see you in that place.
你认为除了那些小毛病外
I suppose you think I've added opium to smoking
我又开始吸鸦片了?
to all of my other little weaknesses?
我仅仅是说
I merely said
在那里见到你让我很吃惊
I was surprised to see you there.
见到你我也很吃惊
As indeed I was to see you.
我在找一位朋友
I was searching for a friend.
我在找一位敌人
And I for an enemy.
敌人?
An enemy?
倘若在那里有人把我认出来了
Had I been recognized in that place
我的性命顷刻就会断送
my life would not of been worth an hours purchase.
马车!
Cab!
我身处在一个最不可思议的调查中
I'm in the midst of the most remarkable inquiry.
我希望你没有吸那烟管里的东西 福尔摩斯
I hope your not smoking the substance in that pipe Holmes.
只为了融入环境稍吸了一点
Only to the extent necessary to merge with the surroundings.
我要去肯特郡的李镇
I'm off to Lee in Kent.
你来吗?
Are you coming?
当然
Of course.
现在应该安全了 华生
I think we shall be safe now Watson.
拿一下缰绳好吗?
Would you take the reins?
我们到底去哪?
Where exactly are we going?
松园
The Cedars,
一栋漂亮的别墅
a lovely villa
在肯特郡靠近李镇的地方
near Lee in Kent.
能否问一下 我为什么要在三月的星期五
May I ask why I'm going to Lee in Kent
半夜三更的 跑到肯特郡的李镇?
in the middle of the night? On a Friday in March?
因为你是我值得信赖的伙伴以及忠诚的朋友
Because you are my trusty comrade and my loyal friend,
我可能两样都需要
I may need both.
这是我掌握的一些情况
Here are the facts, as I understand them.
几年前 有位叫内维尔・圣克莱尔的
Several years ago there came to Lee in Kent,
绅士来到肯特郡的李镇
a gentleman by name Neville St. Clair.
他购置了一栋大别墅 叫松园
He took a large villa, The Cedars,
大约一年后
and about a year later
娶了当地一家酿酒商的女儿为妻
married the daughter of a local brewer.
现在有两个小孩
They have two small children.
他在几家公司里都有股份
He has interests in several companies
每天早上进城
and travels to the city every morning,
每天晚上在坎农街
returning by the 5:14 train
乘五点十四分的火车回家
from Cannon Street every night.
他没有不良爱好
He is a man of temperate habits,
是一位好丈夫
a good husband,
慈爱的父亲
an affectionate father
在朋友间很受欢迎
and is popular with all who know him.
他的负债
His debts,
迄今为止我们所能查明是
as far as we can ascertain,
八十八磅十先令
amount to eighty-eight pounds and ten shillings
而其在首都郡县银行的
while he has two hundred and twenty pounds
账户上
to his credit
有两百二十磅存款
in the Capital and Counties Bank.
因此 没有理由认为
Therefore, there is no reason to think
他存在财务上的困扰
that money troubles have been weighing down.
蹩脚的模仿
Manageable parody.
华生
Watson,
你的话中有一丝怀疑的语气
there's a hint of skepticism in your voice,
这可对你没什么好处
which does you no credit.
我想圣克莱尔太太告诉你
I expect Mrs. St.Clair came to you
她的丈夫失踪了?
saying that her husband has disappeared?
没错
Exactly!
看来这成为生活中
Well seems to be a continuous thread
不可或缺的部分了
in life's fabric.
华生 怎么回事?
Watson, what is this?
我将忽略你对社会缺陷的
I shall ignore your air of resignation
听之任之的态度 继续介绍案情
to the world's frailties and continue.
请继续
Oh please do.
星期一
On Monday,
圣克莱尔如平常一样进城
St. Clair left for the city as usual.
他临走前答应
Before he left he promised that he would
给孩子们带一盒积木
bring home a box of building bricks for his children.
积木?
Building bricks?
好好记下来 华生
Mark that well Watson.
他走后不久 圣克莱尔太太
Soon after he left, Mrs. St. Clair
收到一封电报
received a telegram
说在亚伯丁运输公司的办事处
to say that a parcel of considerable value
有一件寄给她的
had arrived for her at the offices
相当昂贵的包裹
of the Aberdeen Shipping Company.
她决定进城
She decided to travel to the city,
收取包裹
collect her parcel,
吃午饭并进行购物
have lunch and do some shopping.
她意外地发现
It was by chance
自己走到了上天鹅闸巷
that she found herself in Upper Swandam Lane,
那条我们今晚
that same vile alley
都拜访过的肮脏的小巷 华生
that we both visited this evening, Watson.
而正在此时
And it was at this point
一件非常奇怪的事情发生了
that something quite singular took place.
(穷困的人)
请施舍点钱吧
Money please.
快走开!
Get out of here!
内维尔!
Neville!
你想上哪去?
Where are you going?
我要上楼
I'm going upstairs.
楼上没有人
There's nobody upstairs.
我见到我的丈夫在楼上招手
I saw my husband waving from an upstairs window.
楼上没人
There is nobody upstairs.
我见到他了
I saw him.
我认得自己的丈夫
I know my own husband.
他来这里干什么?
What's he doing here?
楼上没有人
There is nobody upstairs.
内维尔!
Neville!
出去
Go on.
他们把她赶出去了?
And they threw her out?
没错
They did.
那个马来人和印度人
The malay and the lascar,
是那栋房子的主人
who owns the establishment.
一个劣迹昭彰的人
A man of the vilest antecedents
把一个杀人凶手放进了酒馆
sent a murderer into the bar.
杀人凶手?却没有受到制裁
A murderer?Yet he goes free.
房子的后屋向着河
And the rear of a building backs onto the river.
那甚至还有一扇活板门
There's even a convenient trap door
作抛弃尸体之用
for the disposal of bodies.
为什么警方不逮捕这两名杀人凶手呢?
Why don't the police arrest these two murderers?
华生 警方逮捕了一个瘸子
Watson, the police have arrested a cripple.
还有很长的案情没给你介绍完
There's so much more yet to tell you
但我们已经到达松园了
but here we are at The Cedars.
谢谢
Thank you.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
有进展吗?
Any news?
圣克莱尔太太
Mrs. St. Clair
我以为你已经入睡了
I thought you'd be asleep.
在这种时候
Sleep does not come easily
想安然入睡并不容易
at a time like this.
这位是我的朋友兼同事华生医生
This is my friend and colleague Doctor Watson
慷慨地答应
who has kindly agreed
协助我进行调查
to help me in my investigation.
福尔摩斯先生提起过你
Mr. Holmes has spoken of you.
圣克莱尔太太
Mrs. St. Clair.
我擅作主张请医生
I have taken the liberty of asking the doctor
在此处过夜
to stay overnight.
而我擅作主张
And I took the liberty
准备了一顿冷晚餐
of preparing a little cold supper.
华生医生你坐我的位置吧
Oh Doctor Watson you take my place.
万万不可
Oh no really.
华生 圣克莱尔太太是位非常执着的女性
Watson, Mrs. St. Clair is a very strong willed woman,
最好不要冒险拒绝她
you refuse her at your peril.
谢谢
Thank you.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生
Now Mr. Sherlock Holmes
在用餐前
before we eat
我想问你几个直截了当的问题
I should like to ask one or two plain questions
希望能得到坦率的回答
to which I should like plain answers.
当然 夫人
Certainly Madame.
你打心底里认为
Do you in your heart of hearts
内维尔还活着吗?
think that Neville is still alive?
请坦白回答
Frankly now
我既不会歇斯底里
I'm not hysterical
也不会晕厥
nor am I given to fainting.
那坦白地说
Frankly then,
我不认为
I do not.
你认为他已经死了?
You think he is dead?
是的
I do.
谋杀?
Murdered?
我没这么说
I didn't say that.
或许
Perhaps.
那他是什么时候死的呢?
And on what day did he meet his death?
星期一
On Monday.
那怎么解释我在今天
So then how do you explain
星期五 收到他的来信呢?
that I received a letter from him today,being Friday?
现在 圣克莱尔太太
Now Mrs. St. Clair
你能否帮我个忙?
I wonder if you would do me a favor?
竭尽所能
By all means.
我已经将你被驱逐出那栋房子
I have told Doctor Watson what happened
之前的案情向华生医生介绍过了
up to the moment when you were ejected from that building.
你能告诉我们随后发生的事情吗?
Would you tell us what happened subsequently please?
告诉华生医生吗?
For Doctor Watson's benefit?
也告诉我
And for mine.
我得将所掌握的他们的信息
I too have to reexamine the facts,
重新梳理一遍
as we know them.
如果你还不是太疲倦的话
Now if you're not too tired.
没问题
Of course.
你可以想象得到
As you may imagine
我对被强行赶出
I do not take kindly
这件事是绝对无法容忍的
to being forcibly removed from a building.
我便寻求警察的帮助
I sought and found police help.
几名巡佐和巡官?
Two constables and Inspector?
布莱斯特里特
Bradstreet.
然后你们返回那栋房子?
And then you returned to the building?
是的
Yes.
两次拜访间隔了多久?
The period of time between these two visits was?
大概二十分钟
About twenty minutes.
我们回去的时候
By the time we returned
门没有上锁
the door was unbolted.
我肯定是那个印度人
Though I'm sure the lascar
在我离开以后把锁打开的
had bolted it when I left earlier.
我要检查你楼上的房间
I want to look at your upstairs rooms.
楼上没人
There's nobody there.
如果楼上没有人 你就没理由拒绝我检查
If there's nobody there you can't object that I look.
你们俩留在这里
You men stay here.
他就在这间房里!
He was in this room!
我说过好多回了
Time and again I tell you,
这里没人
there's nobody here.
能检查一下那间房吗?
May we look in that room?
你不必担心这位男子 圣克莱尔太太
You mustn't be worried by this gentleman,Mrs. St. Clair.
他是警察局的老朋友了
He's an old friend of the constabulary.
你知道 警官
You know, Inspector,
根据W・S・吉尔伯特所说
according to W. S. Gilbert,
警察的生活不是愉快的生活
a policeman's life isn't a happy one.
布恩先生是位职业乞丐
Mr. Boone is a professional beggar.
不是乞丐
No, not a beggar
是位诚实的商人
an honest trader.
他住在这里吗?
Does this man lodge here?
是的
Yes.
你说没有人住在这里
You told me nobody lived here.
夫人 这个乞丐算不上是人
Madame, the beggar is nobody.
你们要是用刀剑刺我们 我们不是也会出血的吗?
If you prick us do we not bleed?
莎士比亚 布恩先生
Shakespeare, Mr. Boone,
我知道这句话 你以前跟我说过
I know that one you've told it to me before.
巡官?
Inspector?
这是泰晤士河 圣克莱尔太太
That would be the Thames Mrs. St Clair?
这是扇大窗户
And the large window.
圣克莱尔太太
Mrs. St. Clair
窗户与河十分接近
a window and a river in close proximity
并不必然与暴力致死划等号
does not automatically mean violent death.
过去一个小时你一直在这里?
You been here in the past hour?
是的
Yes.
还有人来过这里吗?
Anyone else been here?
唉 没有 我如一朵流云独自在此
Alas, no, I've been as lonely as a cloud.
丁尼生?(维多利亚时代最杰出的诗人)
Tennyson?
华兹华斯(英国浪漫主义诗人) 巡官
Wordsworth, Inspector.
他就站在这里
He was standing here.
我见到他
I saw him.
圣克莱尔太太 没有证据表明
Mrs. St. Clair there is no evidence
他曾经来过这里
to suggest that he was ever here.
积木 巡官
Building bricks, Inspector.
的确
So I see.
我丈夫今早进城前
My husband left for the city this morning
跟我说的最后一句话
and the last thing he said to me
就是要给女儿买盒积木
was that he had to buy some building bricks
做生日礼物
for our little girl's birthday.
我明白了
I see.
你们哪位买过积木?
Either of you gentlemen buy building bricks?
肯定是有人落在这的
Somebody must have left them.
这些是我丈夫的衣服!
And these are my husband's clothes!
你确定?
Are you sure?
在你检查的时候需要我
Shall I describe them to you in detail
细细形容吗?
as you examine them?
我丈夫的裁缝名叫斯马德
My husband's tailor's name is Smud
如果你检查一下标签就会发现
if you care to examine the label.
从那时起 布莱斯特里特巡官
At that moment Inspector Bradstreet
开始相信我的话
began to believe my story.
他和他的手下
He and his men
对那栋楼进行了地毯式搜索
made an extensive search of the building
在窗台上发现了血迹
they found a bloodstain upon the windowsill.
他们搜查了那个马来人 印度人和布恩
They searched the malay, the lascar and Boone
但什么也没找到
but found nothing.
他们无法找到我丈夫的大衣
They failed to find my husband's overcoat.
什么
Well.
大衣?
Overcoat?
唯一一件无法
The one item of clothing
找到的衣物
that was not accounted for.
直到退潮
Until low tide.
很重 长官
It's heavy sir.
被什么东西坠得很沉
Weighted down with something.
总共有四百二十一便士
There were four hundred and twenty-one pennies,
两百七十半便士
two hundred and seventy halfpennies
塞满大衣的每个口袋
stuffed into every pocket of the overcoat.
你的结论 华生
Your conclusion Watson.
你尽管说 华生医生
Speak freely Doctor Watson.
过去的一个星期里
I've lived with every possibility
无论多可怕的可能性我都想过了
this past week however hideous.
凶手一定是
The murderer must have been
乞丐布恩
Boone the beggar.
还有什么人会有
Who else could have access to
如此大量的便士和半便士?
such a vast number of pennies and halfpennies?
警方也是如此认为
That is the conclusion reached by the police.
他们逮捕了布恩
They've arrested Boone
他现在在船首街的警察局里
and he is presently in Bow Street Police Station.
尽管我的丈夫仍然活着
Even though my husband is still alive.
圣克莱尔太太
Now Mrs. St. Clair
让我们来重新考究
let us reexamine
这封信的重要性
the significance of this letter.
我能给华生医生读一下吗?
May I read it to Doctor Watson?
当然可以
By all means.
谢谢
Thank you.
亲爱的 不要害怕
Dearest, Do not be frightened,
出了一个极大的错误
there is a huge error,
可能需要一点时间纠正
which it may take some little time to rectify.
耐心等待 内维尔
Wait in patience. Neville.
用铅笔
Written in pencil
写于书的空白页
on the flyleaf of a book,
八开的书 没有水印
octavo size, no watermark.
由一名拇指肮脏的男子于格雷夫森德寄出
Posted in Gravesend by a man with a dirty thumb.
这不是你丈夫的笔迹?
This is not your husband's writing?
不是
No.
但这封短信是?
But the note is?
毫无疑问
Without question.
这是他匆忙时常用的笔迹
It's the hand he always used when he was in hurry.
给信封封口的人
Whoever gummed down the envelope
没有正确地处理信封
handled this very much in error.
有嚼烟叶的习惯
Been chewing tobacco.
这是个微不足道的细节 华生
This is a trifle, of course, Watson
但微不足道的细节最重要
but there is nothing so important as trifles.
圣克莱尔太太
Mrs. St. Clair
信里还有个附件?
there was an enclosure?
他的图章戒指
His signet ring.
圣克莱尔太太
Mrs. St. Clair
你丈夫是否提起过
has your husband ever spoken of
上天鹅闸巷的黄金酒馆?      从未提起过
the Bar of Gold in Upper Swandam Lane?        Never.
华生医生可能
I suspect that Doctor Watson
想问你一个问题
has a question to put to you.
这个问题不好开口
This is a difficult question to ask
圣克莱尔太太
Mrs. St. Clair
你的丈夫有没有任何
but has your husband ever shown
吸食鸦片的迹象?
any signs of taking opium?
他举止总是非常正常
He always appeared perfectly normal
但我得坦白
though I confess
我不懂辨认迹象
I would not recognize the signs.
有什么迹象?
What are they?
无精打采
Well a listlessness,
缺乏活力
a lack of energy,
无法集中精神
an inability to concentrate,
对一切都缺乏兴趣
a general air of apathy.
华生医生对
Doctor Watson is a specialist
无法控制的瘾疾很在行
at uncontrolled addiction.
我丈夫没有沉迷于鸦片
My husband was not an opium addict,
换言之他不吸食鸦片
that's to say is not an opium addict.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
我知道你认为我丈夫已经身亡了
I know you think my husband is dead.
我完全意识到
I fully realize
那封信可能写于星期一
that letter could have been written on Monday
只是在今天才寄出
and only posted today.
我知道他们
I know the circumstances
所列举的种种情形
as they have been described
都不可避免地得出
lead to the inescapable conclusion
他已被谋杀这一结论
that he has been murdered
但同样我也知道
but equally I know
他还活着
that he is alive.
我们之间有着紧密的联系
There's such a keen bond of sympathy between us.
如果他遭遇不幸我会感应到的
I should know if evil came upon him.
请帮我找到他
Please help me to find him.
华生 如果内维尔・圣克莱尔
Watson if Neville St. Clair
还活着并且毫发无损
is alive and well
为什么不回家来证明这一点呢?
why doesn't he come home and demonstrate the fact?
因为他可能已经不在人世了
Well presumably because he's not alive and well.
是 但这封信呢?
Yes but this letter?
可能写于任何时候
Could have been written at any time.
可能写于极度痛苦之时
Perhaps under distress.
也可能是精心伪造的
It could even be a skillful forgery.
那这枚图章戒指呢?
And this signet ring?
很容易取下来
Easily removed,
特别是从一具尸体上取下来
especially if the victim is dead.
的确
Indeed.
回到内维尔・圣克莱尔
Preceding on the hypothesis
已经死了这一假设
that Neville St.Clair is dead,
他是怎么死的呢?
how did he meet his death?
很明显是被谋杀的
Well clearly he was murdered.
被谁谋杀的?
By whom?
警方认为是那个叫布恩的家伙
Well the police think it was this chap, Boone.
我十分赞同警方的看法
I see no reason to disagree with the police.
除了...
Except...
除了什么?
Except what?
你说他是个瘸子?
You say he's a cripple?
是的
Yes.
他的残疾有多严重?
How severe is his disability?
只是有一点跛
Has only a slight limp.
我的行医经验告诉我
Well my medical experience tells me
通常当一条腿有缺陷时
when there is a weakness in one limb
作为补偿
it's very often compensated for
另一条腿会变得非常健壮
by exceptional strength in the others.
无法说服你?
You're not convinced?
这名男子是个职业乞丐
This man is a professional beggar.
在城里很出名
He's well known in the city.
也很受欢迎
He's well liked in the city.
我见过他许多次了
I've seen him many times.
他巧舌如簧
He has a remarkable faculty for repartee
极能取悦施舍他的人
with which he delights his many clients.
听起来没什么危害性
Well he sounds harmless.
既然如此 警方为什么要逮捕他
Why, therefore, did the police arrest him
而不是那个印度人呢?
rather than the lascar?
这正是我向巡官
That is the very question
布莱斯特里特提出的问题
that I put to Inspector Bradstreet.
用排除法可以肯定
The murder has obviously been committed
凶案肯定发生了
by process of elimination.
布恩一定是凶手
Boone must be the murderer.
这些是内维尔・圣克莱尔的衣服?
Are these Neville St. Clair's clothes?
为什么排除了那名印度人的嫌疑?
Why did you eliminate the lascar as a suspect?
因为圣克莱尔太太
Because Mrs. St. Clair
见到她丈夫在楼上的一扇窗户旁
saw her husband in an upstairs window
正在与人搏斗
apparently in the middle of a struggle.
她从楼下的门进去
She went to a downstairs door
被印度人拦住了
and was confronted by the lascar.
当她在跟我们讲述时
While we were conversing
更确切的说
or to be more precise
当那个印度人和他的助手
while the lascar and his assistant
将圣克莱尔太太赶出门时
were ejecting Mrs. St. Clair from the building
楼上的搏斗仍未停止
the fight was proceeding upstairs,
并且导致
leading as we now know
内维尔・圣克莱尔的死亡
to the death of Neville St. Clair.
二十一岁的生日礼物
A twenty first birthday present.
极其注意细节的人
A man of meticulous habits.
没有划痕
No scratches.
谋杀圣克莱尔的动机是什么?
What was the motive in killing St. Clair?
还有待调查
That remains to be established.
没有鸦片的气味
Not a trace of opium
有可能是抢劫吗?
Could it have been robbery.
不 不
No. No.
圣克莱尔的钱包还在口袋里
St. Clair's wallet was in his pocket,
分文未少
the money untouched.
怎么解释大衣里的硬币?
How do you explain the coins in the overcoat?
我无法回答 福尔摩斯先生
I cannot truly answer that Mr. Holmes.
我来试试
Let me try.
布恩将圣克莱尔杀死后
Boone killed St. Clair.
脱去其外衣
He removes the outer garments
企图将衣服及衣服内的物品换成现金
hoping to capitalize on them and their contents.
他抬起尸体
He lifts the body,
穿过房间
carries it across the room,
将尸体推出窗口
forces it through the open window,
由此导致皮肤擦伤
hence the abrasion,
血滴落在窗台上
blood upon the windowsill,
他将尸体放入河中
he releases it into the river...
潮水将尸体卷走
Where it's sucked away by the tide.
在这一系列行为期间
In the midst of this activity
他听见圣克莱尔太太想
he hears the scuffle downstairs
强行闯入所发出的吵杂声
as Mrs. St. Clair tries to force her way in.
时间宝贵
There's not a moment to be lost.
必须将衣物处理掉
Must dispose the clothing.
他从大衣着手
He starts with the overcoat.
并马上意识到
He realizes, at once,
大衣不会沉入水中
it will float and not sink
他是怎么做的?
so what does he do?
他迅速穿过房间来到
He rushes across the room
某个秘密藏宝地
to some secret hall
里面均为其乞讨所得
where he's accumulated the fruits of his beggary,
将所有能拿到的硬币
stuffs all the coins that he can lay his hands on
放进大衣的口袋里
into the pockets of the overcoat...
然后将其扔进河中
And drops it into the water.
如果你和你的手下没有赶到
And would presumably have done the same
其他的衣物
with the other garments
也会落得同样的下场
if you and your men had not arrived.
他将这些衣物藏到帘子后面
Conceals the other garments behind the curtain
希望不会被发现
and hopes they'll not be noticed
如果不是圣克莱尔太太如此坚持
and they would not have been noticed
则会正中其下怀
had Mrs. St. Clair not been so persistent.
巡官 无论那个毒窝
Inspector, whatever plot has been hatched
在酝酿何种阴谋
in that opium den
我认为那个印度人
I cannot but imagine
都脱不了干系
that the lascar is not somehow involved.
我当天极想逮捕他
I was sorely tempted to arrest him on the day.
我现在就派几个人过去
I'll send a couple of men up there now.
不
No.
巡管
Inspector,
如果你允许
with your permission,
我可以提出另外一个策略吗?
may I suggest an alternative strategy?
当然可以
By all means.
让我来拜访这个毒窝
Let me visit the opium den
谨慎低调
discreetly,
乔装打扮
incognito.
就能得知我们想要知道的
We shall learn what we may.
那你有什么收获?
But what did you learn?
一无所获
Nothing.
据我调查所知...每一个人
Everybody... as far as I can ascertain,
都在说真话
appears to be telling the truth.
我无法弄清总体情形
I cannot see an over all pattern.
你呢 华生?
Can you see a pattern Watson?
我无法弄清
I see no pattern
我只见到一位女士
but I do see a woman
不顾所有的客观情形
who despite all objective circumstances
仍然坚信她的丈夫仍然在世
still believes that her husband is alive.
而你多次说过
And you said on many occasions
一位女士的感觉
that the impression of a woman
可能远比分析推理
may be more valuable than the
所得的结论来得有价值
conclusion of an analytical reason.
是啊
Yeah.
但如果他还活着
But if he is still alive.
他在哪里?
Where is he?
我不知道
I have no idea
但我却有个急迫的请求
but I do have an urgent request.
现在已经是凌晨四点多了
It's now well past four in the morning,
我可以睡了吗?
may I go to sleep?
当然
Certainly.
谢谢
Thank you.
华生
Watson.
几点了?
What time is it?
拂晓
Dawn.
我才睡了两个小时
I've only had two hours sleep.
你能不能
I wonder if you'd do me
好心帮个忙
the very great kindness
考虑一下起个床呢?
of considering the possibility of waking up?
我想你有个起床的好理由
I assume you have a good reason.
你想一起跑一趟吗?
Are you game for a drive?
当然
Certainly.
但非得这么早吗?
Does it have to be this early?
我想验证我的一个小设想
I have a little theory I wish to test.
有人命悬一线吗?
Is anyone's life at stake?
当然没有
Certainly not.
可以在早上的晚些时候
Would it be possible to test your theory
再验证你的设想吗?
a little later this morning?
五分钟后楼下见
I'll see you downstairs in five minutes.
五分钟
Five minutes.
出发 尼尔森
Come on Nelson.
你在保持缄默方面真有天赋 华生
You have the grand gift of silence Watson.
让你成为一位难能可贵的同伴
It makes you quite invaluable as a companion.
华生 你正在
Watson you're in the presence
全欧洲最笨的笨蛋面前
of one of the most absolute fools in Europe.
你太夸张了 福尔摩斯      在你起床的时候
You exaggerate Holmes.        I deserve to be kicked
我就该被踢到查林克罗斯去
from here to Charing Cross.
你叫醒我的时候
The moment you woke me up
那我该准备好...      我掌握事情关键了 华生
I would have been prepared to...        I've got the key Watson
就在这个袋子里
here in this Gladstone bag.
早上好 先生们
Good morning gentlemen.
华生 我得承认
Watson I confess
我跟鼹鼠一样瞎
I have been as blind as a mole,
但现在学聪明
but it's better to learn wisdom later
总比不学好
than to never learn it at all.
布莱斯特里特
Bradstreet.
我已经就那个乞丐布恩的事来电话了
I've called about that beggar man, Boone.
他在监狱里 福尔摩斯先生
He's in the cells Mr. Holmes.
我能为你效劳吗?
What can I do for you?
我很想见见他
I should very much like to see him.
他可能还在睡觉呢
He'd probably be asleep.
绝大多数人可能都在睡觉 福尔摩斯
Most of the population is probably asleep Holmes.
好 福尔摩斯 华生医生
Very well Holmes, Doctor Watson
这边走
if you'll come this way.
能把你的袋子留在办公室吗 福尔摩斯先生?
You can leave your bag in the office Mr. Holmes?
我要拿着
I'll take it with me.
那里有关键
It contains the key.
他是个肮脏的无赖
He's a dirty scoundrel.
很肮脏
Filthy.
不肯洗澡
Refuses to wash.
说洗澡会削弱人的抵抗力
Says washing weakens a man's resistance.
在睡觉
Asleep.
他真是个美人 是吧?
He's a beauty isn't he?
巡官 烦请你尽可能
Inspector would you do me the great goodness
小声地将门打开 好吗?
of opening the door as quietly as possible?
先生们 容我为你们介绍
Gentlemen, let me introduce you
来自肯特郡李镇的
to Mr. Neville St. Clair
内维尔・圣克莱尔先生
of Lee in the county of Kent.
天老爷啊
Great heaven.
是的
It is true
请问我被控何罪?
and pray what am I being charged with?
被控谋杀
Charged with making away
内维尔・圣克莱尔先生
with Mr. Neville St. Clair.
谋杀我自己?
Well making away with myself?
我当了二十七年警察了
I've been on the force for twenty-seven years.
这回真是得奖了
This takes the cake.
但很明显
But since it is obvious
没有任何凶案发生
that no crime has been committed
我是被非法拘留
I am illegally detained.
我一人的力量胜于十人
My strength is the strength of ten
因我心灵纯净
because my heart is pure.
亚弗烈・丁尼生(维多利亚时代最杰出的诗人)
Alfred Lord Tennyson.
你向你的妻子撒谎 圣克莱尔先生
You lied to your wife Mr. St. Clair.
这也是纯净吗?
Is that purity?
希望你们理解
Let it be understood
我宁愿忍受牢狱之灾
that I would have endured imprisonment,
甚至死刑
even execution,
也不愿将我这个可耻的秘密
rather than reveal my miserable secret
透露给我的妻儿
to my wife and children.
那就现在透露 圣克莱尔先生
All is now revealed Mr. St. Clair.
好吧
So be it.
我父亲曾是切斯特菲尔德的教师
My father was a schoolmaster in Chesterfield
我受过良好的教育
I've received an excellent education.
酷爱旅行和表演
Traveled, took to the stage
最后成为伦敦
and finally became a reporter
一家报社的记者
in a London newspaper.
有一天 我的编辑
One day my editor
想要一系列关于
wished to have a series of articles
首都乞讨状况的报道
upon begging in the metropolis,
而我自动请缨
and I volunteered to supply them.
因此你成为一名乞丐?
So you became a beggar?
是的
Yes.
而你当演员的经历
And your experience as an actor
肯定大派用场
must have proved invaluable.
是的
Yes.
的确
Exactly.
我给自己化妆
Yes I painted my face
弄得自己一副可怜相
to make myself look as pitiable as possible.
还弄了骇人的伤疤
I manufactured frightening scars.
我用肉色熟石膏
I twisted my lip
把嘴唇一边向上扭卷起来
for the aid of a piece of flesh colored plaster
戴上深色假发
and then with a dark wig
配以合适的服装
and appropriate clothing
在首都
took my position
最繁华的地方蹲点
in the busiest part of the metropolis,
以卖火柴的名义 实际上
ostensibly as a match-seller but, yes,
是一名乞丐
really as a beggar.
你收入颇丰?
And you did well?
是的
Yes.
一天之内讨到二十六先令和四便士
In one day I took twenty-six shillings and four pence.
我为报社写了文章
I wrote my articles for the newspaper.
我的编辑很高兴
My editor was delighted
我也就再也没想过这件事了
and I thought no more about it
直到有一天 我为一位朋友
until one day I backed a bill
背书担保了一张票据
for a friend of mine,
后来接到传票
had a writ served on me
让我赔偿二十五镑
for twenty-five pounds.
我头脑一片空白
Well I was at my wits end
我该怎么办?
I mean what could I do?
突然计上心来
And then suddenly an idea came to me.
我向雇主请了两星期的假
I asked for a fortnight's holiday from my employers
在城里四处乞讨
and spent the time in the city begging.
不消十天
In ten days I had the money
我就筹够钱还债
and was able to pay back the debt.
这时我就陷入了泥潭
That was when I fell into the trap.
你当时在报社
How much were you earning
的收入是多少?
from the newspaper at this time?
一周两镑
Two pounds a week.
远不及乞讨
Far less than begging.
是的
Yes.
过去几年我的年平均收入
During the last few years I had earned, on average,
最少有七百英镑
at least seven hundred pounds a year.
但这是一名绅士的恶行
But that's a gentlemen's guilt.
冷静点 布莱斯特里特
Calmly Bradstreet.
可以很中肯地说
I think it's pertinent to say
圣克莱尔先生不是名普通的乞丐
that Mr. St. Clair is no ordinary beggar.
人们不会料到一个乞丐
People do not expect a beggar
能大量引用莎士比亚
to quote extensively from Shakespeare,
狄更斯先生
Mr. Dickens,
圣经
the Bible
或者最流行的乐曲
or the latest popular songs.
乞丐王子
An aristocrat among beggars.
我知道我不该如此说
Well it is not for me to claim such a distinction
但正如巡官观察所得
but as the Inspector rightly observes
我有一份体面的收入
I had a gentlemen's income
因此如绅士般生活
so I proceeded to live like a gentleman.
我在肯特郡买了栋别墅
I bought a villa in Kent
娶了一位漂亮
I married a beautiful
有身份的女士
and respectable woman
每天早上
and every morning I traveled
我进城"上班"
to my business in the city.
此时你肯定和
You must have been embroiled
印度人混熟了?
with the lascar by this time?
为了使用他楼上的房间
Yes I paid him a generous rent
我支付了一大笔租金
for the use of his upstairs rooms.
他会守口如瓶
My secret was safe with him.
我与窃贼为伍
I fell among thieves
却在他们中发现信誉
but found honor of a sort.
每天早晨
You see every morning
我化妆成肮脏的乞丐
I would emerge as a squalid beggar
每天晚上
and every evening
又换上体面的服装
transformed into a gentleman.
跟我们说说星期一的事
Tell us about Monday.
那天乞讨结束后
I had finished for the day
在鸦片馆楼上的
and was dressing in my room
房间里更衣
above the opium den
突然我看出窗外
and suddenly I looked out of the window
让我恐惧和吃惊的是
to my horror and astonishment
我妻子在街上
there was my wife in the street.
她目不转睛地看着我
Her eyes fixed full upon me.
内维尔!
Neville!
我赶紧去找那个印度人
I ran along to try and find lascar.
你不能让她进来
You must not let her in.
我会告诉她楼上没人
I'll say there is nobody upstairs.
她可能会带警察来
She may return with the police.
我会告诉他们楼上没人
I'll tell them there's nobody upstairs.
布恩先生在楼上
Mr. Boone will be upstairs.
布恩先生是位房客
Mr. Boone's a lodger.
他有权利待在楼上
He has a right to be upstairs.
内维尔!
Neville!
我又再次化妆成
I then became Boone,
乞丐布恩
the beggar once more.
我突然想到
And then it occurred to me
警察可能会搜查房间
that there might be a search of the room
我的衣服可能会出卖我
and that my clothes might betray me.
因此我将用于
So I picked up my coat,
存放我乞讨收入的
which was weighed down with the coins
皮袋子中的硬币
that I had just transferred
塞进大衣里
from my leather bag
以增加重量
in which I carry my takings.
对其他衣服我也打算如法炮制
The rest of my clothes would have followed,
但此时此刻
but at that moment
警察到了
the police arrived.
剩下的事你们也知道了
The rest you know.
我们在窗台上发现血迹
We found blood on the windowsill.
在我匆忙打开窗户时
In my haste to open the window
把自己割伤了
I cut myself.
一个小伤
A minor abrasion
除非你戳我
but if you prick me.
因此我因涉嫌
And thus I was arrested
谋杀自己而被捕了
on suspicion of having murdered myself.
因此你让你妻子极度痛苦
And thus you caused your wife much anguish.
但我给她写了封信
But I wrote her a letter.
而且你让印度人帮你寄出?      是的
And gave it to the lascar to post?        Yes.
但却没有寄出
It was not delivered.
信昨天才寄到
It arrived yesterday.
他可能把信交给他的某个水手顾客了
He probably gave it to one of his sailor customers.
我永远无法原谅自己
I shall never forgive myself,
让自己的妻子遭受如此痛苦
the agony, which I have inflicted upon my wife.
我可以回家了吗?
Can I go to her now?
我们必须提个条件
I think we must impose one condition
圣克莱尔先生
Mr. St. Clair.
任何条件
Anything.
你从此不可再化妆成布恩
There must no be more of you Boone.
我用最郑重的
I swear it by the most solemn oath
方式起誓
that a man can take.
永别了 布恩
Farewell sweet Boone.
愿成群的天使们用歌唱抚慰你安息
A flight of angels sends me to thy rest.
威廉・莎士比亚
William Shakespeare.
破烂熊字幕组